<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 06:00:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Four Ways to Use Discount Coupons to Achieve Your Objectives</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/four-ways-use-discount-coupons-achieve-objectives/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/four-ways-use-discount-coupons-achieve-objectives/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 06:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Using coupons in e-commerce has become a commonplace marketing strategy, but is very effective when done correctly. With one in two purchases being made with a promotional code, not using them would be a mistake. Nevertheless, how can you avoid reducing your margin and losing revenue without using promotions? In this video, experts from online [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/four-ways-use-discount-coupons-achieve-objectives/">Four Ways to Use Discount Coupons to Achieve Your Objectives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Using coupons in e-commerce has become a commonplace marketing strategy, but is very effective when done correctly.</p>
<p>With one in two purchases being made with a promotional code, not using them would be a mistake.<span id="more-22941"></span></p>
<p>Nevertheless, how can you avoid reducing your margin and losing revenue without using promotions? </p>
<p>In this video, experts from online marketing specialist Selldorado explain that the success of your promotional strategies lies in the objectives you want to achieve. They provide details on how to use coupons to achieve the 4 main objectives of an e-commerce site. </p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbv4Fb_ZiHU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=selldorado">Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/four-ways-use-discount-coupons-achieve-objectives/">Four Ways to Use Discount Coupons to Achieve Your Objectives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/four-ways-use-discount-coupons-achieve-objectives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five tips for a successful redesign of your site’s graphic interface</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-successful-redesign-sites-graphic-interface/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-successful-redesign-sites-graphic-interface/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 06:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22820</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Your store has been online for several months now. Sales are picking up, and now you’re looking to take things to the next level. You’ll need to set yourself apart and create an even stronger identity for better credibility. In other words, you’ll need to redo your site’s graphic interface. Most of the work will [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-successful-redesign-sites-graphic-interface/">Five tips for a successful redesign of your site’s graphic interface</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your store has been online for several months now. Sales are picking up, and now you’re looking to take things to the next level. You’ll need to set yourself apart and create an even stronger identity for better credibility. In other words, you’ll need to redo your site’s graphic interface.<br />
<span id="more-22820"></span><br />
Most of the work will be done conjointly with a web agency, the objective being to attract, convince and win over even more potential customers!<br />
It’s a defining moment in the development of your online business, one that should not be taken lightly if you want to maximize your chance for success.</p>
<p>To help you out, here is some valuable advice from the web agency Axome:</p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/erGeDq8V8uo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=axome">Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-successful-redesign-sites-graphic-interface/">Five tips for a successful redesign of your site’s graphic interface</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-successful-redesign-sites-graphic-interface/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Tips for a faster E-Commerce Website</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-tips-faster-e-commerce-website/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-tips-faster-e-commerce-website/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 14:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cindy Deguingand]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22922</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>By Timme Hosting The page speed or site speed is a particularly important aspect for a website and even more so for an online shop. Nevertheless, the issue of page speed is often neglected. Everyone has experienced the following situation at least once: you are on a slow site, waiting and waiting for the page to [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-tips-faster-e-commerce-website/">6 Tips for a faster E-Commerce Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By <a href="https://timmehosting.de/">Timme Hosting</a></p>
<p>The page speed or site speed is a particularly important aspect for a website and even more so for an online shop. Nevertheless, the issue of page speed is often neglected. Everyone has experienced the following situation at least once: you are on a slow site, waiting and waiting for the page to load. Finally frustration sets in and you leave the website, hoping to have better luck finding what you were looking for on another, faster website.</p>
<p><span id="more-22922"></span></p>
<p><a name="tw-target-text3"></a>Basically we know that page speed affects the satisfaction of visitors and that Google made it an official ranking signal in 2010. So it makes sense to deal with the subject in order to make use of the full potential. The faster the better.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #25b9d7">Page Speed affects the Conversion Rate</span></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The load time of a website can affect its conversion rate, which is an important statistic for e-commerce. Long load times not only cause frustration and dissatisfaction in visitors but more likely potential customers will abort and leave to buy from another supplier.</p>
<p>Amazon, an e-commerce giant, has calculated that a load time of more than 100 milliseconds will reduce sales by approximately 1%. Even higher are bounce rates in the area of mobile shopping.</p>
<p>According to an international study from 2015, nearly two thirds (65%) of online shoppers abort and leave a website if loading time exceeds three seconds.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #25b9d7">How to optimize Page Speed</span></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b></b><span style="color: #fbbb22"><i>1. Image size</i></span></h3>
<p><a name="tw-target-text4"></a>Images play an important role in the optimization process. Modern websites often include large and high-resolution images. Using compression and choosing a suitable file format can already have a big impact not only on file size but page speed. So it can make quite a difference whether a PNG, GIF or JPG image file is used.</p>
<h3><b></b><span style="color: #fbbb22"><i>2. File size</i></span></h3>
<p><a name="tw-target-text5"></a>But the file size and thus loading time can not only be reduced in the case of images. You should ensure a clean source code, free of useless characters, empty spaces and comments. Embedded CSS and JavaScript files should also be merged and compressed.</p>
<h3><b></b><span style="color: #fbbb22"><i>3. Avoid redirects</i></span></h3>
<p><a name="tw-target-text6"></a>A relaunch for example can lead to the use of redirects. Each redirect results in a request to the server, increasing the time to load a page. Therefore, redirects should be checked regularly to find out if maybe some of them are unnecessary and can be avoided. Particularly, chains of redirects should not be used at all.</p>
<h3><b></b><span style="color: #fbbb22"><i>4. Use browser caching</i></span></h3>
<p><a name="tw-target-text7"></a>The browser can store once retrieved website content in its cache. This will reduce the time to load if the website is visited again. In order to benefit from this, you should enable browser caching for your website. Otherwise, the browser will request all the data again from the server on the next visit.</p>
<h3><b></b><span style="color: #fbbb22"><i>5. GZIP compression</i></span></h3>
<p>A server side way to compress your website data is provided by GZIP. Especially for text based files of a website (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), GZIP is particularly suitable. Compression makes the files smaller and the loading times faster.</p>
<h3><b></b><span style="color: #fbbb22"><i>6. Hosting</i></span></h3>
<p>Where you host your website or your online shop, which hosting provider you chose, plays a very important part when it comes to load times and page speed. Because even a perfectly programmed and optimized website will perform badly when hosted on a slow server.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In addition to state of the art hardware, the used web server is crucial. An nginx server is high performance and requires much less memory than other web servers. Thereby it can answer more queries per second simultaneously. Even with a lot of website visitors there is little impact on the loading time.</p>
<p>A good hosting service can provide important advice on how to further improve the page speed of your website through the use of PHP 7 or technologies such as HHVM and HTTP/2 for example.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><b></b><span style="color: #25b9d7">Tools to improve Page Speed</span></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A good point to start optimizing the page speed of your website is to take a look at the information Google offers about your website. In Google Search Console you can see how long it takes Google to load the pages of your website.</p>
<p>Using Google&#8217;s PageSpeed Insights you can have your website analyzed by Google in terms of page speed. Google then offers fairly detailed suggestions of improvement both for desktop as well as mobile devices. By following those suggestions and improving your website based on them you should already be able to speed things up.</p>
<p>Tools such as webpagetest.org or pingdom.com offer the opportunity to get to know the</p>
<p>loading process of a website in more detail. The server connection with all the requests and answers to and from the web server are shown in a detailed diagram. That helps to identify potential.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-tips-faster-e-commerce-website/">6 Tips for a faster E-Commerce Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-tips-faster-e-commerce-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Deyson, Ambassador of the month &#124; February 2017</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-deyson-ambassador-month-february-2017/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-deyson-ambassador-month-february-2017/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 09:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[floreravaud]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Ambassadors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22900</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Deyson is our extremely dynamic Ambassador in Rio de Janeiro. He’s always ready to give a talk about PrestaShop or answer your questions. Deyson is always up to something within the city of Rio, a major city in Brazil, where ecommerce is booming. We are very proud to have him at our side to promote [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-deyson-ambassador-month-february-2017/">Meet Deyson, Ambassador of the month | February 2017</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Deyson is our extremely dynamic Ambassador in Rio de Janeiro. He’s always ready to give a talk about PrestaShop or answer your questions. Deyson is always up to something within the city of Rio, a major city in Brazil, where ecommerce is booming. We are very proud to have him at our side to promote the solution in Brazil, that’s why we chose him as Ambassador of the month of February 2017. Do you want to know more about Deyson? Then read the article below.<span id="more-22900"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About you</h2>
<p><strong>Three words to best describe you:</strong><br />
Entrepreneur – Committed – Persistent</p>
<p><strong>If you were to write a book about yourself, what would you name it?</strong><br />
The Eternal Apprentice</p>
<p><strong>What is your hidden talent?</strong><br />
I am a Kenhi, 1st DAN of Kendo by All Japan Kendo Federation</p>
<p><strong>A favorite line from a movie? </strong><br />
&#8220;And what you have done as a team is connect people, connect those people to information. Which is what we do. And more than that, you have the courage to dream. In spite of your obvious and astonishing limitations&#8230;you never gave up on that dream.&#8221; &#8211;  The Internship (Vince Vaughn &amp; Jared Stern)</p>
<p><strong>If you could travel anywhere right now, where would you go and why?</strong><br />
I would go to Alaska, I think it must be an amazing place&#8230; wild nature!</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About your country</h2>
<p><strong>What is your favorite local food or drink?</strong><br />
<em>Bobó de camarão</em> is a dish of Afro-Brazilian cuisine.<br />
Creamy consistency, is made with shrimp sautéed in green spices and coconut milk, mixed in mashed aipim and more palm oil, ginger and dried shrimps. To drink… Coconut water.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/food.jpg" alt="food+drink" width="956" height="500" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22904" /></p>
<p><strong>Give us a fun fact about your country:</strong><br />
Carnival… In Brazil we have carnival, a very lively party that takes place in February. People come from all over the world to see our carnival.</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About PrestaShop</h2>
<p><strong>What is your favorite PrestaShop store?</strong><br />
I do not have one favorite, but I like this shop: <a href="http://www.nature-vie.com/" target="_blank">http://www.nature-vie.com/</a></p>
<p><strong>What opportunities does PrestaShop provide in your country?</strong><br />
Brazil has its own characteristics due to its size, but also due to issues related to the economy.</p>
<p>Brazilians see entrepreneurship as a life option. This is why Brazil is a country with huge possibilities. In my opinion, as a digital marketing professional, the challenge at the moment is to generate visibility for PrestaShop and to promote its adoption, in order to transform PrestaShop into a synonymous of online store.</p>
<p><strong>What is your feedback on the new major version, PrestaShop 1.7?</strong><br />
PrestaShop 1.7 represents a very big evolution and demonstrates the vitality of the platform. This creates a lot of security when choosing the platform to build an online store.</p>
<p>The performance in presenting the products on any devices is excellent. In the case of Brazil, mobile performance is fundamental.<br />
Looking at the new Back office, I noticed the developers&#8217; concern about facilitating the administrative actions inside the store with the presentation of a clean, well-organized and easy to use environment.<br />
I really liked this new version!</p>
<h2 style="color: #df0067">About being an Ambassador</h2>
<p><strong>What is your proudest moment as a PrestaShop Ambassador?</strong><br />
I am very proud when I present PrestaShop as an effective solution for an entrepreneur. I am also extremely proud when I hear someone who adopted PrestaShop and created his store after attending one of my meetups.</p>
<p><strong>What do you like the most about being an Ambassador?</strong><br />
I am very committed to guiding entrepreneurs to start their business with PrestaShop. I will be happy to continue to help the community as much as I can. Becoming an Ambassador was a great way to help other people and overcome the difficulty of speaking in public and even from going to enjoy lecturing.</p>
<p>Today, not only do I speak in meetups, but I also make presentations in technical schools, trade associations, social projects and much more&#8230; I am always ready to talk about PrestaShop!</p>
<p><strong>A last word?</strong><br />
Thanks to the PrestaShop team for the support and opportunity, for my part I will make many presentations and promote many Meetups about PrestaShop here in Rio de Janeiro in 2017 <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p><strong>Thank you very much Deyson!</strong><br />
Find out more about <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/ambassador/deyson-thom%C3%A9" target="_blank">Deyson’s profile</a> and <a href="https://www.meetup.com/PrestaShop-Rio-Ecommerce-Meetup/" target="_blank">join his meetup group.</a>&#8221;<br />
Do you want to become a PrestaShop Ambassador? <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/application-form" target="_blank">Apply now.</a></p>
<p>See you next month <img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-deyson-ambassador-month-february-2017/">Meet Deyson, Ambassador of the month | February 2017</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/meet-deyson-ambassador-month-february-2017/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three reasons eCommerce companies should frequently update product prices</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/three-reasons-ecommerce-companies-frequently-update-product-prices/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/three-reasons-ecommerce-companies-frequently-update-product-prices/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 09:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22893</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Every eCommerce company aims to build a sustainable and profitable business. To do so, they should focus on their pricing strategies. Every business, large or small, can benefit from finding new ways to optimize product pricing. But this doesn’t happen by simply assigning a monthly price list to the whole catalog. On the contrary, when [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/three-reasons-ecommerce-companies-frequently-update-product-prices/">Three reasons eCommerce companies should frequently update product prices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every eCommerce company aims to build a sustainable and profitable business. To do so, they should focus on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-12/" target="_blank">their pricing strategies</a>. Every business, large or small, can benefit from finding new ways to optimize product pricing. But this doesn’t happen by simply assigning a monthly price list to the whole catalog. On the contrary, when it comes to pricing, merchants should get as creative as possible with their marketing efforts, because different <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-22/" target="_blank">pricing strategies</a> can dramatically affect their bottom line. Here are three very clear reasons why every eCommerce company should always test and optimize their prices.</p>
<p><span id="more-22893"></span></p>
<h2>1- There’s always room for improvement—or a price increase</h2>
<p>Every eCommerce company faces competitors that are ready to swoop in and welcome customers who abandon carts on your site for a better deal elsewhere. But this doesn’t mean you should engage in a “race to the bottom.” While you may lose some shoppers to competitors who slash prices, you are likely to win new customers who are more interest in a loyal relationship than a one-off sale. Consider focusing on shoppers who already prefer your business and are likely to continue buying from you, even if your prices are slightly higher than what they might find elsewhere.</p>
<p>Many eCommerce companies play the best-deal game too aggressively. They end up with prices that are so low, even a 5% increase isn’t likely to impact the performance of their best-sellers. This is an opportunity to test a price increase. Using specialized software, companies access an overview of what their competitors are charging for key product categories. Armed with this intelligence, companies can make precise decisions regarding small price increases that allow them to remain competitive. Ideally, you’ll find a balanced price that brings in more money for each item sold, while still maintaining a “best deal” position that attracts buyers.</p>
<h2>2- Lower costs to increase profitability</h2>
<p>Prices and costs are on opposite sides of the profitability equation.</p>
<p>In eCommerce, costs regularly fluctuate. A product’s unit cost is determined from a multitude of factors that change over time. The major share of the unit product cost in eCommerce is the supplier cost, in other words, the unit sales price on the supplier side. The remainder of the unit cost comes from marketing spend and overhead costs for staff, facilities, etc.</p>
<p>Supplier costs are a big deal for eCommerce companies of all sizes. Deciding on supplier cost generally comes down to two factors: purchase volume and negotiating power. The first is rather simple: the more you buy of a product, the less each individual unit costs. However, negotiating power is more fluid and depends on many factors, like the company&#8217;s market position, the state of the retailer-supplier relationship, whether it’s long-standing or newly established, etc. ECommerce companies should aim to lower unit costs by managing these two variables as smartly as possible.</p>
<p>Marketing budget and overhead costs also change over time. It’s worth putting energy into optimizing them because they will directly impact the final unit cost.</p>
<h2>3- Your competitors are changing their prices all the time</h2>
<p>One of the most important competitive forces in eCommerce is pricing. Online shoppers around the world love a good deal, and they won’t hesitate to drop one company for another if they find one.</p>
<p>So while eCommerce merchants should avoid price cutting themselves into a corner, they still need to work out a competitive pricing strategy. Finding what this means for each market implies keeping an eye on the competitive landscape, and assessing how pricing decisions will be felt by customers.</p>
<p>Keeping prices constant, instead of changing them to reflect market movements, puts companies at risk of losing out on profit opportunities and new customers. But doing this intelligently requires competitive pricing knowledge. One of the best and most affordable ways to gain insight is to use an automated competitor price tracking software that suggests price change decisions as soon as they become relevant. The flexibility that <a href="https://prisync.com/?utm_source=prestashop&amp;utm_medium=textlink" target="_blank">automated competitor price tracking and monitoring software</a> brings translates to more frequent opportunities to maximize profits. Smart price adjustments made based on competitor insight can be a powerful tool for eCommerce companies to remain competitive and profitable.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>ECommerce is a competitive landscape, but companies who seek to understand their competition will see it become a strength rather than a threat—start by building a competitive pricing strategy.</p>
<p><strong>About the Author</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-21929" alt="6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_4" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_4.png" width="144" height="177" />Burc Tanir is an SMB-loving, eCommerce evangelist and the CEO of Prisync.com, the competitor price tracking software, already serving companies from more than 40 countries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/three-reasons-ecommerce-companies-frequently-update-product-prices/">Three reasons eCommerce companies should frequently update product prices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/three-reasons-ecommerce-companies-frequently-update-product-prices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to get a profitable online store by setting an ideal shipping price</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-profitable-online-store-setting-ideal-shipping-price/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-profitable-online-store-setting-ideal-shipping-price/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 14:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22865</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Shipping orders is one of the most important parts of running an online store. In fact, there is no other way to reach your customer? Lots of companies are offering shipping solutions with multiple delivery methods. The fact remains that shipping is expensive,  a domestic shipment already costs around 5€ to 6€. Moreover, customers expect [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-profitable-online-store-setting-ideal-shipping-price/">How to get a profitable online store by setting an ideal shipping price</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shipping orders is one of the most important parts of running an online store. In fact, there is no other way to reach your customer? Lots of companies are offering shipping solutions with multiple delivery methods. The fact remains that shipping is expensive,  a domestic shipment already costs around 5€ to 6€. Moreover, customers expect the delivery of their orders to be free, as this is standard the major ecommerce companies like Zalando. A big part of the online retailers cannot offer free delivery, as it is too expensive.. That’s why it’s important to implement the right shipping price strategy for your online store. 64% of online shoppers abandon their shopping cart because of too high shipping costs. This is why it’s important to set the right strategy for your shop.<br />
<span id="more-22865"></span><br />
<b>The secret behind your shipping costs</b></p>
<h2>Shipping costs</h2>
<p>It all starts with calculating your exact shipping costs. It would be useless to think about the right pricing strategy, without knowing how much you are exactly paying for a shipment. The price you pay for shipping your parcels depends on a number of things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dimensions of the package</li>
<li>Weight of the package</li>
<li>National or International delivery</li>
<li>Tracking</li>
<li>Insurance</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Packaging and branding costs</b></p>
<p>But that’s not all. Packaging costs  are an essential part of shipping your products. If you use basic packaging, the costs are relatively low, but if you choose for a customized package design, costs can rise quickly. Don’t forget to check what your competitors are doing with their packaging. Are they keeping it simple with basic packaging? Then it might be a good idea to use customized packaging for your online store to differentiate. Research by Dotcom distributions showed that 52 percent of consumers are likely to make repeat purchases from an online retailer that delivers orders in premium packaging.</p>
<h2>Returns</h2>
<p>Returns, the nightmare of every online retailer, have a big influence on the shipping costs. After all. you are obligated to reimburse the purchase price of the order, including the shipping costs if a customer returns their package. This is something most online retailers tend to forget, however being transparent about your returns policy can lead to a profitable shipping strategy. The following examples shows that shipping costs are influenced by returns:</p>
<table width="602" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top"><b>Total shipping costs</b></td>
<td valign="top"><b>Actual purchases</b></td>
<td valign="top"><b>Costs for 1 shipment</b></td>
<td valign="top"><b>Shipping costs  per purchase</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top">€500</td>
<td valign="top">85</td>
<td valign="top">€5</td>
<td valign="top">€5,88</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The total cost to ship 100 orders is €500, but 15 customers return their order. This results in an shipping cost of €5,88 per actual order.</p>
<h2>4 possible shipping strategies and how to utilize them successfully</h2>
<p><b>Free shipping as from a certain threshold: </b>Free shipping on all orders is (for most online stores) not profitable. That’s why a lot of online retailers offer free shipping above a certain threshold. By doing so, you make sure that your margins are large enough to compensate the free shipping policy. You also encourage customers to buy more in order to get free shipping. It is important to test what threshold works best for your online store. If your threshold is too high, you might put off customers, however if your threshold is too low, you will lose profit. You can easily test this by setting up an A/B test in your online store. Suppose your current threshold is €75 and you set it to €50. Then it’s important to follow up the influence of this change on your margin:</p>
<p>Conversion improvement: +18%<br />
Average order value: -12%</p>
<p>Net margin/order: -9%<br />
<b>⇒</b><b> Improvement in net profit/visitor: 1,18*0,88 * 0,91 = -5%</b><b><br />
</b><br />
This example shows that lowering your threshold will not always lead to more profit. Therefore it’s smart to test different thresholds and to compare results to find your ‘sweet spot’.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Fixed shipping price:</b> Research (of the Canada Post Corporation) has shown that 24% of online stores charge a fixed delivery fee, no matter the value of their purchase . An example of this strategy is offering a certain delivery method for €4,95. Furthermore, the research has shown that this strategy is not the one, since conversion can drop by 50% when no form of free shipping is offered. Still want to keep the fixed shipping fee? Then it’s important to A/B test the fee comprehensively  and discover what happens when you decrease or increase this fee with a certain amount. Do the extra amount of purchases compensate the margin that you lost by lowering your shipping fee?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Free shipping: </b>Offering free delivery to all your customers, regardless of order amount, isn’t possible and profitable for most online stores. Big players like Zalando can afford this strategy, as they get a volume discount from carriers, but smaller online stores do not have the power to negotiate these kinds of discounts. These stores will get burned by low profit margins.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is however a good idea to offer free shipping during specific festivities, as part of your marketing strategy. Free shipping during Christmas, Valentines day or father&#8217;s day can trigger customers to buy at your online store instead of at stores of your competitors. Research of David Bell, of the Wharton School of Business, has shown that consumers are more interested in free delivery (where they can save €6,99 with) than a discount of €10 in your shop.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/Nike-free-shipping.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-22871 aligncenter" alt="Nike-free-shipping" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/Nike-free-shipping-300x200.png" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>An <b>exception</b> on the “free shipping rule” applies to online stores that sell expensive products with a big margin. If you don’t offer free shipping on products that cost more than €100, customers will be displeased.</p>
<p><b>Include shipping fees in product prices: </b>Do you really want to offer free shipping, although your margins are too low to offer it? Then you could consider including the shipping fee (partly) in your product prices. Normally you should sell a product for €55 and ask €2,95  delivery costs. Then it is an option to raise the price to €57,95 and offer free delivery. Applying this strategy, you have to keep track on your competitor’s prices. Your prices might be more expensive with this strategy, which might result in losing customers to your competitor. So keep an eye on your conversion rate when applying this strategy for your online store.</p>
<p><b> Thus, how to make your shipping strategy profitable? </b><br />
The ideal shipping strategy will be different for every online store. Therefore, it is important for you to test different strategies and find the one that’s most profitable. Do you already have a shipping price strategy that works for you? Then dare to experiment with the threshold or fixed shipping fee. You could probably still improve it and make it more profitable. So, to summarize how to get profitable?</p>
<ol start="1">
<li>Never charge the full shipping fee to your customers</li>
<li>Don’t offer free shipping by default</li>
<li>Test with different shipping strategies and keep optimizing</li>
<li>Use free shipping as a marketing tool and communicate this clearly on your product pages and homepage</li>
<li>Take returns into account when calculating your shipping costs</li>
<li>Last but not least: take packaging and marketing costs into account</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-profitable-online-store-setting-ideal-shipping-price/">How to get a profitable online store by setting an ideal shipping price</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-profitable-online-store-setting-ideal-shipping-price/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Offering Subscriptions on your PrestaShop Store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/offering-subscriptions-prestashop-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/offering-subscriptions-prestashop-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22863</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A subscription strategy is relevant for 90% of ecommerce companies. Subscriptions can apply to physical products, virtual products, delivery (through Premium delivery), or services. Offering customers subscriptions or product boxes will help to increase your monthly earnings and build loyalty. Learn how to offer subscriptions to different products, or a delivery service, with your PrestaShop [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/offering-subscriptions-prestashop-store/">Offering Subscriptions on your PrestaShop Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A subscription strategy is relevant for 90% of ecommerce companies. Subscriptions can apply to physical products, virtual products, delivery (through Premium delivery), or services. Offering customers subscriptions or product boxes will help to increase your monthly earnings and build loyalty. Learn how to offer subscriptions to different products, or a delivery service, with your PrestaShop store.<br />
<span id="more-22863"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #1e4848">Subscription Advantages</h2>
<p>For e-sellers, subscriptions are an easy way to <b>ensure recurring revenue each month without having to seek out additional customers</b>. These earnings can grow exponentially! A subscription strategy is one of the most reliable ways to quickly reach earnings objectives and to anticipate income before the start of the month.<br />
Not only is it an easy way to <b>build customer loyalty</b>, but it also makes it <b>a snap to manage your inventory and increase your store&#8217;s conversion rates</b>.</p>
<p>There are several types of subscriptions, depending on visitor expectations and what kind of products you sell.</p>
<h2 style="color: #1e4848">“Boxes”</h2>
<p>There are more than a few box sites! The ever in-style “box” is used for beauty products, baby products, wine, flowers, decorations, jewelry, gourmet baskets, geek items, and so on. <a href="http://www.blooms.fr/" target="_blank">Blooms</a> and <a href="http://www.tiniloo.com/" target="_blank">Tiniloo </a>that run on PrestaShop are nice examples.</p>
<p>Each month, or at an interval you choose, subscribers eagerly await a ‘gift’ item they have subscribed to. What&#8217;s special about boxes is that subscribers don&#8217;t know exactly what theirs will contain until the moment it arrives. The element of surprise is what makes subscribing—and being debited—so worth the wait.</p>
<p>You can offer some products through a box and others through ordinary purchase. You can also offer only boxes, with various prices and sizes, or even just one box to make it even easier to prepare your deliveries!</p>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Advantages for the e-seller:</h3>
<ul>
<li>recurrent income</li>
<li>very easy to manage inventory</li>
<li>simplified income prediction</li>
<li>loyal customers</li>
<li>identical orders to prepare</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Advantages for the customer:</h3>
<ul>
<li>a unique purchasing process, a new surprise each month, or at another interval</li>
<li>an emotional bond with your store because customers see the box as a ‘surprise gift’</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Necessary features for the site:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/529-subscription-products" target="_blank">a subscription module with recurrent payment</a>, which you can choose from our list.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #1e4848">Subscriptions to physical products:</h2>
<p>The most successful ecommerce businesses offer them, and users couldn&#8217;t be happier! Presented as a sales offer ‘<i>save 10% when you subscribe’ </i>they enable you to quickly improve conversion rates.<br />
With an Amazon Dash button, customers are never without life&#8217;s necessities. You can offer the same for your customers by letting them subscribe to a product through subscription. Young parents will be delighted to receive a pack of diapers for their child at an interval they choose, without having to leave the house, or worry that the product will be sold out. This can apply to any situation, even a B2B solution!</p>
<p>You can offer subscriptions to your entire catalog or only for some products. <a href="https://www.abonnement-cafe.com/abonnement-capsule-nespresso/16-100-capsules-ristretto-nespresso-compatible-8058454036092.html" target="_blank">Abonnement-café</a> is an example of this, offering customers a monthly coffee pod subscription at a tempting price:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-22868" alt="Subscriptions to physical products: " src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/screen-2-1024x534.png" width="700" height="365" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #1e4848">Subscriptions to virtual products and services:</h2>
<p>Domestic help, massage, theater—subscriptions also apply to services, and of course to virtual products: MOOCS (massive open online courses), content, video, music, and more!</p>
<p>For example: <a href="https://shop.quotidiano.net/" target="_blank">Shop Quotidiano.net</a> is an Italian site that lets users subscribe to online newspapers</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-22870" alt="Subscriptions to virtual products and services: " src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2017/02/screen-3-1024x629.png" width="700" height="429" /></p>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Advantages for the e-seller: </h3>
<ul>
<li>recurrent income</li>
<li>simplified income prediction</li>
<li>loyal customers</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Advantages for the customer: </h3>
<ul>
<li>a unified purchasing process</li>
<li>Simplified and exclusive access to products reserved for subscribers</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Necessary features for the site: </h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/529-subscription-products" target="_blank">a subscription module with recurrent payment</a>, which you can choose from our list.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #1e4848">Delivery subscription &#8211; Premium Delivery:</h2>
<p>Delivery fees are responsible for nearly 50% of cart abandons. But if you offer free shipping, your profitability will plummet. We have a solution! You can now offer customers a Premium subscription for shipping, just like Amazon and other prominent e-commerce sites.</p>
<p>Your customers pay for delivery subscription and can take advantage of free or rock bottom shipping rates throughout the duration of their Premium subscription.</p>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Advantages for the e-seller: </h3>
<ul>
<li>loyal customers</li>
<li>increased conversion rates</li>
<li>fewer abandoned carts</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Advantages for the customer: </h3>
<ul>
<li>the satisfaction of ‘saving’ on shipping fees when ordering, and priority delivery.</li>
<li>a solid reason to return to the site where they subscribed to premium delivery</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="color: #1e4848">Necessary features for the site: </h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-costs/24876-shipping-premium-flat-rate.html" target="_blank">a Premium shipping subscription module</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #1e4848">Last but not least</h2>
<p>One more thing—when you set up a subscription service for your store, make sure you:</p>
<ul>
<li>update your terms and conditions of sale</li>
<li>Verify that customers can easily unsubscribe, and let them know through clear communication how hassle-free subscription is with statements like ‘<i>unsubscribe in just a click</i>’ or ‘<i>you can put your subscription on hold at any time</i>.’</li>
</ul>
<p>Doing so puts customers at ease and increases conversion rates for subscriptions.</p>
<p>Happy selling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/offering-subscriptions-prestashop-store/">Offering Subscriptions on your PrestaShop Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/offering-subscriptions-prestashop-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Improve the performance of your e-mail marketing campaigns using an effective prospect database!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-performance-e-mail-marketing-campaigns-using-effective-prospect-database/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-performance-e-mail-marketing-campaigns-using-effective-prospect-database/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Sending e-mails as often as possible to the highest number of customers possible&#8230; That’s a reaction that’s still ingrained, but it can actually cause opening and click rates to fall! The golden rule for boosting campaign results is to put together a top-notch prospect database and qualify it as often as possible! Our e-mail marketing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-performance-e-mail-marketing-campaigns-using-effective-prospect-database/">Improve the performance of your e-mail marketing campaigns using an effective prospect database!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sending e-mails as often as possible to the highest number of customers possible&#8230; That’s a reaction that’s still ingrained, but it can actually cause opening and click rates to fall! <span id="more-22815"></span></p>
<p>The golden rule for boosting campaign results is to put together a top-notch prospect database and qualify it as often as possible! </p>
<p>Our e-mail marketing expert SendinBlue gives you the keys to do so, through five tips listed below. Consider it advice to help you effectively build and maintain your prospect base, thus boosting your sales: </p>
<ul>
<li>Tip no. 1: Start with your customers</li>
<li>Tip no. 2: Attract future customers</li>
<li>Tip no. 3: To qualify contacts, use confirmed opt-in</li>
<li>Tip no. 4: Maximize efficiency</li>
<li>Tip no. 5: Don&#8217;t rest on your laurels</li>
</ul>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_jyNkqzLrw0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=sendinblue">Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-performance-e-mail-marketing-campaigns-using-effective-prospect-database/">Improve the performance of your e-mail marketing campaigns using an effective prospect database!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/improve-performance-e-mail-marketing-campaigns-using-effective-prospect-database/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boost your e-commerce traffic with content</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/boost-e-commerce-traffic-content/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/boost-e-commerce-traffic-content/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22804</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Blogs, social networks posts, newsletters—a handful of ways exist to reach your target audience and attract them to your online store.To succeed, you&#8217;ll need to come up with some relevant and original content! Start by taking an interest in your target group. Consider them above all to be a community united by common interest, and [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/boost-e-commerce-traffic-content/">Boost your e-commerce traffic with content</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blogs, social networks posts, newsletters—a handful of ways exist to reach your target audience and attract them to your online store.To succeed, you&#8217;ll need to come up with some relevant and original content!<span id="more-22804"></span></p>
<p>Start by taking an interest in your target group. Consider them above all to be a community united by common interest, and always observe a number of good practices to ensure your content is visible and shared. </p>
<p>In this video, Nicolas, CEO of E-commerce Nation (the top e-commerce community in France), offers a few tips for successfully creating content and bringing more traffic to your e-commerce site: </p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I8BlN8nmBps?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f;border: 1px solid #b31217;border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=youtube&amp;utm_content=axome">Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/boost-e-commerce-traffic-content/">Boost your e-commerce traffic with content</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/boost-e-commerce-traffic-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five tips to choose the right payment method to grow your online store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22776</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The popularity of an online shop amongst consumers depends increasingly on the selection of payment methods available. At the end of an order process, customers want a selection of payment methods that they like to use and that are both simple and practical. Customers will only complete a purchase and be satisfied with their shopping [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/">Five tips to choose the right payment method to grow your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The popularity of an online shop amongst consumers depends increasingly on the selection of payment methods available. At the end of an order process, customers want a selection of payment methods that they like to use and that are both simple and practical. Customers will only complete a purchase and be satisfied with their shopping experience when this is the case. In a survey carried out by the ECC Cologne e-commerce centre1, 42% of respondents said that they would shop with a competitor if none of their favourite payment methods were available.<span id="more-22776"></span></p>
<h2>You should keep the following five payment tips in mind at all times:</h2>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>1. Provide the optimal payment mix</strong></h3>
<p>An optimal payment mix involves offering three to five different payment methods, including online transactions, card payments and alternative payment methods. Users also prefer when all payment methods are available at a glance. </p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>2. Involve all payment parties</strong></h3>
<p>In order to offer a range of different payment methods, you should work with a payment service provider (PSP) and an acquirer. The PSP ensures that different payment solutions can be integrated smoothly in the online shop. The acquirer has a banking licence and ensures that payments (such as by credit card or giropay) can be accepted and processed. Service providers such as Wirecard offer these essential services from a single source, so only one contract is necessary.</p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>3. Focus on your target group</strong></h3>
<p>Business owners should understand their target groups, particularly when it comes to payment. After all, payment behaviour varies considerably. Men shop in different ways to women, and clothing is paid for differently online compared to software downloads. It is recommended to seek the advice of payment experts in this regard.</p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>4. Do not forget risk management</strong></h3>
<p>Misuse can be costly – for example, when shop operators are left with unpaid invoices. It is therefore advisable to work with a payment service provider who can handle both acquisition and fraud prevention services. This enables potential fraudsters to be identified before a transaction is completed.</p>
<h3 style="color:black"><strong>5. Make sure your payment page is trustworthy</strong></h3>
<p>Most people enjoy online shopping – until they reach the payment stage. Some customers have concerns when they reach the checkout stage at some less well-known online shops. The look and feel of the online shop and the payment page should therefore match and appear trustworthy and secure.</p>
<h2 style="color:black">Wirecard Checkout Seamless – integrate all relevant payment methods into your shop seamlessly!</h2>
<p>Wirecard Checkout Seamless supports all popular payment methods (credit cards, SEPA direct debit, invoices, etc.) on all PCI DSS-compliant devices. The user interface is integrated seamlessly into the online shop and looks the same for all payment methods. The payment solution is also ideal for cross-selling and upselling as goods and services can be added to the basket even after the payment details have been entered. Additionally, Wirecard Checkout Seamless features effective fraud prevention tools.</p>
<p><strong>Wirecard Checkout Seamless is already integrated into PrestaShop core software.</strong><br />
This means that merchants do not have to download and install any software – they just need to activate <a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/en/payment-card-wallet/24188-wirecard-checkout-seamless.html" target="_blank">the free Wirecard module in PrestaShop</a> to use the payment solution.<br />
Visit Wirecard at this year’s Internet World in Munich (7–8 March 2017, hall A6, booth D214) to find out all you need to know about payments in person.</p>
<p><em>Source: ECC Cologne e-commerce centre: Payment im E-Commerce Vol. 19 – Der Internetzahlungsverkehr aus Sicht der Händler und der Verbraucher (Online payments from the perspective of merchants and consumers) http://shop.ecc-handel.de/de/Themen/Payment-Pricing/Payment-im-E-Commerce-Vol.-19- Der-Internetzahlungsverkehr-aus-Sicht-der-Haendler-und-der-Verbraucher</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/">Five tips to choose the right payment method to grow your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/five-tips-choose-right-payment-method-grow-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
